Guide to the Naomi Shihab Nye Papers
The Wittliff Collections
- Works, 1963-2017; 30 boxes
  - Publications, 1969-2017, undated
    - Organica, Magazine of Arts and Activism, 2000-2007 (Box 51)
      Tampa, FLA, incomplete. Regular poetry column by Nye.
  - Artbooks, 1986-2015
    - Arabic Coffee, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Famous, September 1989. (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Mint, 1991 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Travel Alarm, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Carrying Wishes, 1993 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Problems, 2012 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - The Light Gatherers, 2015 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Broadsides, 2006-2017
    - Broadsides (Box 30, Folder 8)
      "The Day," "During a War," "Words Under the Words" quotation," "The Day," "The Shopper," "Kindness," "Wind of Enthusiasm," "The Traveling Onion," exhibition catalog for "Swimmer, Blessed Sea."
    - Broadsides, Oversized (Box 52, Folder 1)
      "Fold," "his life," "It Is Not a Game It Was Never a Game," "Red Brocade," "Big Head, Big Face.".
    - Broadsides, Oversized (Box 54, Folder 7)
      "Broadsheet #1," "…Books and Stationery, Some Still Tied in Bundles, Littered the Street," "A Renga by the Chancellors of the Academy of American Poets."
    - Broadsides, Oversized
      "Swimmer, Blessed Sea," "Kindness," "Sometimes I Pretend," "Elevator."
  - Book Covers and Art, Undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Talks, 1991-2014, undated
    - 1993-2013 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
      Notes and fragments
    - Oversized (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - The Language of Life with Bill Moyers, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Radio appearances, 2001, 2014 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Ashley Bryan Introduction, 1998 (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Includes program, poems, and research
    - Betty Kray (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Includes research
    - Introductions for others (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - "Hockaday School Auditorium", 1991 (Box 31, Folder 6)
      VHS tape
    - 9 optical discs, 1991-2014, undated (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - "Corpus Christi, Naomi Shihab" (Box 31, Folder 8)
      1 open reel audio tape
- Correspondence, 1960-circa 2010s, undated; 7 boxes
  The Correspondence Series is divided into A-Z and Family. Note that correspondence with Virginia Duncan is included in Works-Editor Correspondence. Correspondence A-Z is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and includes personal and business correspondence. Letters and emails may include poems by correspondent; this information and the institution and/or related work by Nye is noted when known. Correspondents with multiple letters are housed in separate folders; these include Roberto (Bob) Bonazzi, Ashley Bryan, Edward Hirsch, Albert Huffstickler, Ted Kooser, Maury Maverick, Jr., Michael W. McCann, William McNamara, William (W.S.) Merwin, John Phillip Santos, William (Bill) Stafford, and Kim and Kit Stafford. Evidence of Nye's personal relationships with several of these poets and their families is in folders of Stella Kerouac, Barbara Stafford Wilson, and in particular Dorothy Stafford and Paula Merwin. Family Correspondence includes the Shihabs and the Nyes, and is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - A-Z, circa 1970s - 2010s
    - A (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Aaker, Linda. Abu Nab, Ibrahim (Trimedia). Adamo, Ralph (The Barataria Review). Adams, Michael (The University of Texas at Austin). Adamshick, Carl. Ahmed, Kamaluddin (Ahmed Publishing House). Alejandro, Ann. Alexander, Kwame. Alexander, Meena. Ali, Ahmed. Allyn, Pam. Amico, Sam. Amir, Ronny. Anderson, Teresa. Anker, Mary. Aragon, Margo and Horace Axtell. Araguz, Jose Angel. Armitage, Simon. Atlee, Champ (The Lawrenceville School). Atwan, Robert (The Best American Essays). Austin, Brad.
    - Ba-Be (Box 32, Folder 1)
      Bachman, John. Baer, Zet. Baker, Kathy. Barghouti, Omar. Barakat, Ibtisam Suleiman. Barbee, Lynne (Journal of Palestine Studies). Barks, Coleman (University of Georgia). Bass, Ellen. Bass, Rick. Bedway, Barbara. Bekoff, Marc (University of Colorado-Boulder). Bell, Marvin. Belul, Sherry R. Ben-Israel, Yael. Benedikt, Michael (The New Yorker). Benka, Jennifer (Academy of American Poets). Bennett, John (Vagabond Press). Berger, Barbara. Berger, Margi. Berryhill, Michael.
    - Bl-Bu (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Blackford, Staige, D. (The Virginia Quarterly Review). Blanco, Albert. Bly, Robert (The Seventies Press). Bodem, Tiffany. Bonazzi, Liz. Bonnerjee, Supreo. Booth. Bottoms, David (Georgia State University). Boullata, Kamal J. Bowles, Brad (University of Colorado at Denver). Brantley, John D. Braun, Robert. Brenner, Marie. Breverman, Harvey. Bristow, Bill (Trinity University). Britton, Marcia Wolter (Wyoming Humanities Council). Brown, Jessie. Brummet, John (Scape). Buchholz, Brad (Austin American-Statesman). Burgess, Lynne. Burke, David W. Burlingame, Robert (Bob). Busch, Charles. Bush, Barbara. Bush, George W. Butt, Charles. Buttimer, Chris.
    - Bonazzi, Roberto (Bob), 1975 - 2005, undated (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Bryan, Ashley, 1995 - 2013, undated (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Busailah, Reja-e, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Ca-Ce (Box 32, Folder 6)
      Calkins, Lucy (Teachers College - Columbia University). Candler, Cynthia. Carlisle, Andrea. Carlstrom, Nancy White. Carrigan, Andrew. Carrigan, Mark C. (Towers Guest Speakers Committee). Carpenter, Nancy. Carter, Betty. Carter, Rosalynn and Jimmy. Castro, Jesse. Castro, Joy. Catacalos, Rosa. Cauthorn, Julia. Cech, John.
    - Ch-Cu (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Charara, Hayan. Chatton, Barbara. Chavez, Denise. Cheng, Gu. Chiari, Margaret (Journal of Palestine Studies). Chomeau, Vinni (Friends of Gibraltar & Write On, Door County). Christians, Carol. Chute, Carolyn. Cichowski, Gregory and Emine. Ciccotelli, Darin. Cisneros, Catherine (URBAN-15 Group). Cisneros, Sandra. Clewell, David. Coffey, Ruth. Colby, Sas. Cole, Peter (Ibis Editions). Collins, Joe. Cook, Molly. Court, Georgia (Poetry Life). Coy, John. Crisp, Margie. Crookston, Carly. Crouch, Helen "Shatzie." Cuba, Nan Brindley. Curling, Brian.
    - Carol Collins and family, February 3, 1997 (Map-case Dr. 9)
    - D (Box 32, Folder 8)
      Dana, Robert. Daniel, John (Wilderness Magazine). Daniel, Kathleen. Darling, Amy. Daventry, Claudia. de la Garza, Dottie Dorothy. DeMarinis, Rick. Der Hovanessian, Diana. Derricotte, Toi (University of Pittsburgh). Derry, Alice. Dick, James (Festival Hill). Dixon, John. Doggett, Lloyd. Donberg, Sharon. Donovan, Joal. D'Ordine, Helen. Doty, Mark. Dressler, Mylene (Guilford College). Dumitru, Crya (St. Mary's University). Dumoran[?], Adele (University of Hawai'i at Manoa). Durham, Daniel. Dwyer, Sue.
    - E (Box 33, Folder 1)
      Edel, Marjorie. Edwards, Judy. Elliott, William (Bill). Ellsworth, Tom (The Madison Review). Enayetullah, Anwar. Erd, Wendy. Escalante, Jim (Iguana Press).
    - F (Box 33, Folder 2)
      Faegre, Aron (Friends of Clyde Rice). Farabee, Mary Margaret and Ray. Fazzino, Carmela (Publicom). Feierman, Joanne. Ferrari, Ed and Patty. Field, Edward (Bantam Books). FitzGerald-Beckett, Zoe. Flato, Ted. Flesher, Vivienne, and Ward Schumaker. Flynn, Robert. Fontenot, Ken. Fountain, Carrie. Fowler, Sandra (Ocarina). Fox, John. Frasier, Debra. Frederick, Joan. Friedman, Gary.
    - G (Box 33, Folder 3)
      Gallimaufry. Galvin, James (Jim) (University of Iowa). Ganesan, Indira. Gibbs, Gary (Texas Commission on the Arts). Gibson, Jewel. Gill, James. Glen, Bob (Shakespeare Festival of Dallas). Goldbarth, Albert. (Wichita State University and The University of Texas at Austin). Graham, Kerry. Graham, Mally. Gray, Patricia (Pat) S. Greenaway, Nancy Walker. Greene, D'Aine. Greene, Graham. Grissom, Coleen, (Trinity University). Grose, Rebecca. Grubin, David. Grubin, Joan. Guerrero, Laurie Ann (Smith College). Gundy, Jeff (Bluffton College). Gurovitsch, Robin and Timothy J. Daniels. Gutowski, Leila Said.
    - H (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Haba, Jim and Erica. Hacker, Marilyn. Haller, Paul. Halpern, Daniel (Antaeus - Ecco Press). Hammad, Suheir. Hammill. Hancock, Tamara. Hanlon, Nöel and Peter Koehler. Hannush, Monica. Harjo, Joy (New Mexico Indian Environmental Education Project). Harst, Rudolf (Rudi)). Hass, Bob. Hassell, Billy. Haukio, Jenni. Haystack Writers, 2010. Hazo, Mary Anne. Hazo, Samuel. (International Poetry Forum). Hearn, Tony. Henkes, Kevin and Laura. Hepburn, Susan. Herring, Marquetta (Paperbacks Plus). Hewitt, Geof. Hillman, Grady. Hilal, Dima. Hinojosa, Tish (with Andreas Sedlmair). Hogan, Linda. Holman, Bill (Georgia State University). Holt, Pat. Howard, Barb and Dick. Howard, Debra. Hsieh, H. Phillip. Humphrey, Katharine. Hasan, Rabiul.
    - Hirsch, Edward, 1989-2000 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      Personal correspondence that spans Hirsch's career at both University of Houston and Grinnell College. Includes letters from Nye to Hirsch and photographs.
    - Huffstickler, Albert, 1978-1996 (Box 33, Folder 6)
      Includes 22 poems by Huffstickler.
    - I-J (Box 33, Folder 7)
      Ignatow, David (York College). Igne, Charles. Jackson, Bruce, 2011 (University at Buffalo). Jahn, Loretta. Jamal, Ghada. Janeczko, Paul B. Jennings, James Longstreet (J.L.) Sibley, Jr. Jepson-Gilbert, Anita. Jewish Women's Committee to End the Occupation of the West Bank & Gaza. Jiles, Paulette and Jim Johnson. Johnston, Tony. Jones, Sandy. Jones, Teresa. Judd, Raymond, Jr. (Trinity University). Junko, Yokota.
    - K (Box 33, Folder 8)
      Ella. Kadri, Frank W. Kaplan, Kathy Walden. Kaufman, Amy R. Kaufman, Shirley. Kaywell, Joan. KAUST School (King Abdulla University of Science and Technology). Kelder, Cralan. Kelley, Deborah Maverick. Kennedy, Caroline. Kerr, Ken and Ann. Kessler, Stephen, November. Kestenbaum, Stu [Stuart] (Maine State Commission on the Arts and Humanities and Haystack Mountain School of Crafts). Khalife, Marcel (Nagam Cultural Program). Khan, Mobarak Hossain (Radio Bangladesh). Khan, Tamam. Kherdian, David. Khewhok, Carol (Shangri-La Center of Islamic Arts and Culture). Kicknosway, Faye. Kiepert Bücher. Kikutani, Naomi. Kim, Leo. King, Sam. Kitchen, Judith. Klunick, Travis. Knight, Etheridge. Knott, Mendy. Kumin, Maxine. Kyse, Helen.
    - Kerouac, Stella, 1972 - 1980, undated (Box 33, Folder 9)
    - Kooser, Ted, 2010 - 2016, undated (Box 33, Folder 10)
    - L (Box 33, Folder 11)
      LaBerge, David (Bard College at Simon's Rock). Landers, Joseph. Lannan, Camille. Lam,Thien-Kieu. Leach, Ann. Lehman (The Best American Poetry). Lee, Amy Freeman. Levine, Naomi. Likeness, Craig (Phi Beta Kappa). Lighthart, Annie. Lindberg, Stanley W. (The Georgia Review). Loeppert, Bessie. Long, Jim (Hawaii Review). Looney, George (Mid-American Review). Lopate, Phillip. Lueders, Edward. Luterman, Alison. Lynch, Robert L.K. Lyne, Sandy. Lynn, Kirk. Lyon, George Ella.
    - M-Ma (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Mackechnie, Anne. Mackechnie, Bill. MacMillen, Ann. Maksoud, Hala (American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee). Maher, Terre. Majaj, Lisa Suhair. Manack, Jessica. Marans, Leonard. Marchant, Fred. Martinez, Dionisio. Mathers, Doug. Mathers, Petra. Mattawa, Khaled (Princeton University). Matthews, Joanne. Matthiessen, Maria and Peter. Maverick, Julia Orynski. Maynard, James (University of Buffalo).
    - Mc-Mu (Box 34, Folder 2)
      McBride, Elizabeth (Domestic Crude). McCormack, Mary, Monique, Molly, Helen, and Luke. McCourt, Ellen Frey. McCracken, Elizabeth. McCrae, Fiona (Graywolf Press). McCrudden, Linda (Kaiser Permanente). McDermott, Karen. McDonald, Emily. McDonald, Rebecca (Becky). McDonald, Walter (Walt) (Texas Tech University). McElderry, Margaret. McKim, Elizabeth Gordon. McLaren, Olga. Melin, Jerry, (Scape). Merchant, Natalie. Miller, Debbie. Miller, E. Ethelbert. Miller, Nancy B. Milligan. Mills, Elizabeth (Betsey) (Southwest Review). Moore, Jim. Moore, Mary (Loon). Morales, Shelly (Driscoll ISD). Morfín, Otero and María Guadalupe. Motika, Stephen (Poets House). Moyers, Bill. Moyers, Judith. Mullen, Harryette. Mueller, Al. Myatt, Rosalind (Women's National Book Association).
    - Mathis, Matthew (Box 34, Folder 3)
      Includes 2 optical disks.
    - Maverick, Maury, Jr., 1990-2003 (Box 34, Folder 4)
      Personal correspondence, nearly all contains articles written by Maverick (including a bio of Nye); also his obituary, correspondence from Nye, and Maverick correspondence to others aparently shared with Nye.
    - McCann, Michael W., 1998 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - McNamara, William (Spiritual Life Institute), 1983-2010 (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Merwin, Paula, 1989 - 2015, undated (Box 34, Folder 7-8)
    - Merwin, William (W.S.), 1989 - 2002, undated (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - N (Box 34, Folder 10)
      Naddy, Amro (Virginia Quarterly Review). Najjar, Nada (University of Toledo). Nathan, Leonard. Nansha China Preparatory Academy (NCPA). Nelson, Michael (Four Winds Press). Niehaus, Alisha (Simon & Schuster). Nims, John Frederick (Poetry). Noelke, Monte.
    - O (Box 35, Folder 1)
      O, The Oprah Magazine. Obama, Barack. Obama, Michelle. Okamura, Larry. Ondaatje, Michael (York University). Orfalea, Greg, (American-Arab Anti-Discrimination League).
    - P-Q (Box 35, Folder 2)
      Padgett, Ron (Teachers & Writers Collaborative). Palmer, William (Bill) (Alma College). Pastiloff, Jennifer. Patterson, Becky Crouch. Paulo, Olivia. Payne, John R. Paz, Octavio. Peacock, Howard. The Perishable Press Limited. Perry, Janet. Peterson, Bob. Picozzi, Kim (Education Service Center, Region 2). Pierce, Jo Carol. Pirtle, Sarah. Peterson, Emma. Poets House. Pomelo Books (Sylvia Vardell and Janet Wong). Poteet, Scott. Qudsi, Adli. Qumsiyeh, Mazin.
    - R (Box 35, Folder 3)
      Radmacher, Mary Ann. Ragain, Maj. Rao, Vimala R. Ray, Mary Lyn. Rice, Clyde. Rice, Clyde and Virginia. Richardson, Rebecca Hanson. Richter, Bob, Scottie, and Peter. Rief, Linda. Riley, Susan. Riordan, Rick. Rips, Geoff. Roberts, Doris. Robitaille, Claire. Rock, Andrew (Street Fiction Press). Rodriguez, Raquel Aurelia. Rodriguez, Rodrigo Joseph. Rosenblum, Gregg (Ploughshares). Rowell, Charles H., (Callaloo). Russelle, Regula (Cedar Fence Press).
    - S-Sa (Box 35, Folder 4)
      Sahid, Leeshan. Said, Edward. Salahuddin, MD, (Karika). Salvner, Gary (Youngstown State University). Samdani, Hussain. Sandeen, Eric J. (University of Wyoming). Sarkar, Shihab (The New Nation). Saroyan, Aram. Saudi, Mona. Sawah, Rihab. Sawaya, Linda.
    - Sc-Sh (Box 35, Folder 5)
      Schneeman, Andrea (Four Wind Press, Simon & Schuster). Schoenberger, Nancy, (The Academy of American Poets). Schulman, Grace. Schumaker, Ward (with Vivienne Flesher). Schroeder, Rubina. Self, Paul. Semel, Nava. Shah, Varsha. Shammas, Anton (University of Michigan). Shamsuzzaman, Abul Fazal. Shefrin, Susan Russell. Shelton, Lois (University of Arizona Poetry Center). Sherp. Shook, Eddie. Shulman, Alix Kates. Shunnarah, Nabella Salama.
    - Si-So (Box 35, Folder 6)
      Simmons, Naomi. Simonson, Rick. Simpson, Mona. Sisneros, Samuel. Smith, Austin. Smith, Curtis. Smith, Dave (William Morrow & Company, Inc.). Smith, Ileene (Summit Books). Somoza, Joseph (Puerto del Sol). Song, Cathy.
    - Sp-Sz (Box 35, Folder 7)
      Spencer, Robert Nye. Spinelli, Eileen. Spinelli, Jerry. St. John, Rick. Stebbins, Christy. Steingesser, Martin. Steves, Patsy. Stewart, Frank (Manoa). Sulzer, Caroline. Sunico, RayVi. Sutton, Roger (The Horn Book, Inc.). Swaney, Anita. Sze, Arthur.
    - Santos, John Phillip, 1977-1997 (Box 35, Folder 8)
    - Sorrell, Elizabeth Nye, 2004 - 2006, undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
    - Stafford-Wilson, Barbara, 1990-2014 (Box 35, Folder 10)
    - Stafford, Dorothy, 1992-2010 (Box 35, Folder 11, Box 36, Folder 1-2)
    - Stafford, Kim, 1988-2015 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - Stafford, Kit, 1995-2005 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Stafford, William (Bill), 1977-1986 (Box 36, Folder 5)
    - T-V (Box 36, Folder 6)
      Taylor-Hall, Mary Ann. Temple, Charles. Theroux, Phyllis. Thomas, Sara. Thornhill, Elizabeth. Traugott, Alexander. Uschuk, Pamela and William Pitt Root. Valencia, Tita. Vens, Susie van de. Verde, Barbara. Villarreal, Marti (Arts America)
    - W (Box 36, Folder 7)
      Waldman, Ana. Ward-Waller, Jeanie and Abbey Walker. Walker, William O. (Bill), Jr., (Trinity University). Wallace, Ian. Wallace, Ian and Deb. Wallace, Ron (University of Wisconsin - Madison). Walsh, Sandra (Duchesne Academy of the Sacred Heart). Way, Curtis (Harford Day School). Wendt, Ingrid. West, M[…], Wevill, David, Wheeler, Susan (Lewis Center for the Arts, Princeton University). White, Andrea. Wilbur, Ellen. Williams, David. Williams, Marilyn. Willihnganz, Jonah (Stanford University). Wilson, Eddie. Wiltgen, Michelle Elizabeth. Winger, Debra. Winik, Marion Lisa. Wittliff, William D. (Bill) (The Encino Press). Wolff, Virginia Euwer. Wood, Susan (Rice University). Woolman, Carol. Wrigley, Robert (Bob).
    - Y-Z (Box 36, Folder 8)
      Yamanaka, Lois-Ann, 1992, 1994. Zisquit, Linda. Zoghaib, Henri. Zuck, Colleen, (Wee Wisdom).
    - First name only, A-C (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - First name only, D-J (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - First name only, K-N (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - First name only, P-W (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - Signed cards from classes and workshops (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Unnamed (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Letters written by Nye, 1991-1999 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      Donnelly, Timothy (Poetry Society). Elleman, Barbara (Book Links). Gwynn, Sam (Lamar University). Jones, Margot C. Karl (Pitt Poetry Series). Karakashian, Levon. Landers, Ann. Madden, Hope. Merrill, Chris (Ars Poetica anthology). "To the Editor." Villareal, Marti (Arts America Program).
    - Notes, addresses, and business cards (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Nye and Shihab Family Correspondence, 1960-2013
    The bulk of the series is composed of correspondence between Naomi Shihab Nye and her parents, Aziz and Miriam Shihab. Also contains correspondence from Nye's husband, Michael Nye, and their son, Madison Cloudfeather Nye. Correspondents also include Mr. and Mrs. C.H. Allwardt (Miriam Nye's parents), Nina and Paul Nye (Michael Nye's parents), Ellen R. Fehr, a cousin, and Nye's brother Adlai and his wife Janis.
    - Adlai Shihab, 2005, 2013, undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Aziz Shihab, 1975-1998, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
      ncludes a translated letter from Yasir Arafat, and letters from Bonazzi and Merwin about the manuscript for Shihab's memoir Does the Land Remember Me?, and Bonazzi's review of the book in the San Antonio Express-News.
    - Ellen R. Fehr, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Janis Shihab, 1989 (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Madison Nye, 1988-2011, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
    - Michael Nye, 1980-1985, undated (Box 37, Folder 10)
    - Miriam Nye, 1977-2014, undated (Box 37, Folder 11-12)
    - Mr. and Mrs. C.H. Allwardt, 1960-1966, undated (Box 37, Folder 13)
      Miriam's letters chronicle a road trip across Colorado in 1965 and impressions of living in Palestine in the summer of 1966. Naomi's letters recount daily life while living in Lee's Summit, Missouri.
    - Nina and Paul Nye, 1990, undated (Box 37, Folder 16)
      Correspondence contains multiple enclosures including photographs (one unidentified and one of Naomi Nye in 1979), religious meditations, and an undated prayer card.
    - Barbara Nye to Michael, Naomi, and Madison, October 1992 (Box 37, Folder 17)
- Instruction, circa 1970s - 2010s
  The Instruction Series documents Nye's considerable teaching work for twelve years in public schools across Texas as part of the Texas Commission on the Arts Writers in the Schools Programs, and in other parts of the United States and particularly the Arabic-speaking world. The bulk of the materials consists of student poems, collected into photocopied or mimeographed publications, many from San Antonio Independent School District schools. Also included are single poems and songs, and student letters and poems, labeled "Testimonials," by Nye. Lesson plans include the "Rutabaga Roo" teacher packet that Nye shared with San Antonio public school teachers as well as many notes. Business Documents include a proposal, CV, reports to the Texas Commission on the Arts and Humanities, and clippings; Adult Instruction includes limited materials related to instruction at Haystack Program in the Arts, American Cultural Center Lahore, Palestine Poetry Festival, and the University of Hawai'i at Manoa, the University of Texas at San Antonio, and the University of Texas at Austin
  - Student Publications, 1975-2012
    - Fever or Forgotten Wings, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      Publication of Texas Commission on the Arts & Humanities. Includes student poems and short notes and photo of Nye.
    - "Deep Dish Poetry Pie", circa Fall 1975 (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      "sometimes i feel like the whole world's a black tuxedo and i'm a pair of brown shoes," "Today Feels Like Frog Legs," "Earth Pizza," "Words from Woodridge," "around the world in an hour and a half"
    - 1979-1980 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      "7 o'clock at San Patricio Street," "Thank You Earth for Holding Us Up," "Words from Woodridge"
    - 1980-1985 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      "The Rainbow's Son and the Mermaid's Daughter," "My Head is Like a Spaceship," "The Heart Flies Home," "Corsicana Voices and Verse."
    - "Living is Number One: Songs by Children for Children", 1983 (Box 38, Folder 6)
    - Undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
      "Looking Back," "Rounding Up the Stars"
    - 1999, 2012 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      "Somebody's Story," "Anthology of Student Poems."
    - Mimeographs and floppy disk, 1979, undated (Box 38, Folder 10)
    - Calendars, 1978-1980 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Edited by Others, 2008-2011, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Student Poems, circa 1970s - 2010s
    - "(13) Ways to Look", 1984-1999, undated (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Poems and lessons, 2005-2014, undated (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Testimonials, circa 1975-1981 (Box 39, Folder 4)
      Letters from students to Nye, most include poems or drawings.
    - Letters to Nye, circa 1994-2016 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      Include poems or drawings
    - Letters from ACS, circa 2010 (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - KAUST School, circa 2010 (Box 39, Folder 7)
      Include poems or drawings (King Abdullah University of Science and Technology)
    - "Inside Out" (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Instruction for Children
    - "Rutabaga-Roo Teacher Packet" (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - "Story Poems-Narrations" (Box 39, Folder 9)
      Student exercises and ideas.
    - "Comparisons" (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - "Science as Springboard" (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Notes on teaching (Box 39, Folder 12)
      Writings, exercises, ideas, notes. Includes lessons titled "Monday," "Tuesday," Haiku," "Poetry of Leadership," and loose notes.
    - Lessons on Nye works (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - Student art - poetry projects on Habibi (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Business Documents, Texas Commission on the Arts and Humanities, 1975-1978 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Adult Instruction, 1988-2013
    - Writers' Anthology, Haystack Program in the Arts, 1988 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Lesson Plans (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - American Cultural Center Lahore, 1983 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - "Jerusalem", 1992-1993 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Palestine Poetry Festival
    - University Documents, 1984, 1991, 2013 (Box 40, Folder 6)
      University of Hawaii, University of Texas at San Antonio, University of Texas at Austin - Michener Center.
- Appearances and Awards, 1974-2017, undated
  - Appearances, 1977-2017, undated
    - Appearances (Box 40, Folder 7-10, Box 41, Folder 1-5, Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Oversized Posters, circa 1982-circa 2014 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Oversized posters, 1995-2015, undated
    - Nametags (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Awards, 1974-2017, undated (Box 42, Folder 3-6)
- Writings on Nye, 1970-2017, undated